VIVIAN AKPU

Lagos State, Nigeria. 100225. Phone: +234(0)8165041002. www.linkedIn.com/in/vivian-akpu

E-mail: <u>benedictvivienne@yahoo.com</u> www.github.com/vivianakpu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An experienced data analyst and business intelligence expert with three (3) years of experience. My expertise in data visualization, statistical analysis, and business acumen enables me to drive well-informed decision-making and optimize strategies. My strong communication skills allow me to effectively convey complex findings to stakeholders, making me a valuable asset in transforming data into valuable business solution.

Willing to relocate ANYWHERE

SKILLS

- Data Analysis
- SQL (PostgreSQL, MsSQL)
- Data Visualization
- Problem-Solving
- Time Management
- Team-work

- Communication Skills
- Data Processing and Data Cleaning
- Statistical Knowledge
- Data Exploration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE & ACHIEVEMENTS

JANUARY 2021 - TILL DATE

CLIENT SERVICE OFFICER 1

Key Responsibilities:

SAINT NICHOLAS HOSPITAL

- Assisting clients/patients with requests for information, complaints, making appointments and resolving issues.
- Familiarizing and keeping up-to-date with changes in the hospital's plans and tariffs.
- Resolving telephonic and e-mail inquiries in a timely manner.
- Escalating queries to the senior manager where necessary.
- Grant pre-authorizations for medical treatment, if covered.
- Designed templates for patients number and visitors tags in a cost effective way.
- Trained and Mentored my junior colleagues, ensuring they are well-equipped to execute tasks effectively and seamlessly transition.

Achievement(s):

■ Awarded staff of year in 2022 and 2023 and for executing my duties professionally and excellently.

JANUARY 2024 - JUNE 2024

DATA ANALYST (REMOTE)

Key Responsibilities:

CAREER INSIGHTS

- Conducting analysis using tools like SQL, PowerBI.
- Collaborating with team members virtually to understand data requirements and projects goals.
- Cleaning and transforming data to maintain accuracy and consistency in analysis.
- Developing reports and dashboards to visualize data and communicate findings effectively.
- Managing time effectively to meet deadlines and deliver high-quality analysis remotely.

SEPTEMBER 2022 – JULY 2023

BUSINESS ANALYST (REMOTE)

Key Responsibilities:

- Conducting analysis using tools like Excel, Python, Tableau.
- Cleaning and transforming data to maintain accuracy and consistency in analysis.
- Conducting market reports and trend analysis to provide valuable insights for decision-making.
- Adhering to the project timelines and delivering great quality analysis, create visualizations, and recommendations for remote settings.

NOVEMBER 2017 - OCTOBER 2018

NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORP (ENGLISH TUTOR)

Key Responsibilities:

COMMUNITY SECONDARY SCHOOL, IGBOGENE

ELIAS ELECTRONICS COMPANY

- Taught English language and related subjects.
- Assisted in the creation of an adult school in Igbogene Community.
- Organized and executed seminars, rallies and lectures on the importance of education and ways to eradicating illiteracy.

Achievement(s):

■ Awarded by the Bayelsa State Ministry of Adult Mass Literacy for an exceptional contribution to the community.

PROJECTS

Hospital Emergency | | SQL, Excel and PowerBI – March 2024

- Cleaning and organizing the data
- Creating interactive dashboards and reports in PowerBI to visualize key metrics like; patients wait time based on medical departments, analyzing patients demographics and medical conditions, identifying trends in ER visits.\
- Presenting result to the hospital management for decision-making.

DATA TOOLS

SQL (PostgreSQL)	•	PowerBl
■ Excel	•	Python
■ Tableau	-	PowerPoint

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Analysis and Business Intelligence

DIGITAL BANANAS
JANUARY 2024

Basic Life Support (BLS) Certified

AMERICAN HEART ASSOCIATION

FEBRUARY 2022

Soft Communication Skills

JOBBERMAN

Registered Teacher (Certified)

TEACHERS REGISTRATION COUNCIL OF NIGERIA

2017

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2021

Delta State University, Abraka, Delta State

2013-2017

Bachelor of Education, B. (ED) English Education

2008 - 2011

Uwangue Secondary School, Warri, Delta State

West African Examination Council (WAEC)

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST